

Website: https://flora8984461.github.io/

**Telephone**: (+1) 819-775-1837 | **Email**: <u>yliu538@uottawa.ca</u>

**PROFILE** 

Excellent communication with experience working in a diverse environment.

Inquisitive and continually in professional development and skill building.

Internship experience in web design & development.

Advanced proficiency in a variety of UI design and web programming tools.

**SKILLS** 

programming C, Java, JUnit, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Ajax, PHP, Python, MySQL

Framework JQuery, ReactJs, VueJs, Laravel, Django, Bootstrap

CMS WordPress, Drupal

Design Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator, Axure, Balsamiq

Other tools Vagrant, Git, Docker, AWS, MS Office

**EXPERIENCE** 

01.2020- Frontend Developer Intern, AedoAl, Gatineau, CA

current Write testing in Mocha and Jest to QA React web applications

Assist in developing and improving React application functions

09.2019- Student Web Developer, uOttawa IT Web Service, Ottawa, CA

current Execute tests to validate the functionality of applications managed by the

team (PHPUnit)

Help with designing and developing web applications (Drupal, PHP, MySQL)

09.2019- Webmaster, IEEE SPAC 2020, Ottawa, CA

current Build the website for IEEE SPAC 2020, including front-end UI design (HTML5,

CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, etc.) and implementing back-end function (Python,

Django)

05.2019- Front-End Web Developer Intern, CIA School, Ottawa, CA

08.2019 Used Adobe suits to make mockups and prototype the websites

Used web programming (HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, etc.) to develop

websites and improved user experience

Developed web applications for online study system used by teachers and students and fulfilled interaction between backend and frontend (Ajax,

Python, Django, MySQL, etc.)

01.2019- 04.2019	Website Manager (Volunteer), RCEN, Ottawa, CA
	Redesigned the website for RCEN, making it updated and more user-friendly (PHP, Drupal, JQuery)
01.2019-	Teaching Assistant & Corrector, University of Ottawa, CA
Current	ITI1121 - Introduction to Computing II: Java programming, and experienced QA test tools such as JUnit
	GNG1106 – Fundamentals of Engineering Computation: C programming
06.2019-	Customer Experience Representative, Chapters Indigo, CA
09.2019	Handled customer interactions, giving detailed, personalized, friendly & polite service to ensure customer

## **EXTRA ACTIVITY**

09.2019-	Professional Development Club Founder & VP, University of Ottawa, CA
current	Develop strong industry networks and relationships among students and professors
	Offer advice and support to students in technical professional skills development
09.2019- current	System Science Graduate Student Association Founder & Secretary, University of Ottawa, CA
	Organize events, maintain the website and help make decisions to support students with better experience
	Be the bridge of communication between students and the department
03.2019-	Member of Engineering Faculty Council, University of Ottawa, CA
current	Represent students in system science to participate in faculty meetings
	Help with council decisions and coordinate with students

## **EDUCATION**

09.2018- current	Master of System Science - Department of Computer Science & Electrical Engineering, University of Ottawa, CA
	Courses include Computer Science, Electrical & Computer Engineering and E-business Technology
09.2014- 06.2018	Bachelor of Engineering, Hubei University, CN Courses included Mathematics, Programming, engineering, etc.